Prateek Chatterjee

<u>prateekpc.ux@gmail.com</u> - 508-471-0199 - <u>Portfolio</u> - <u>LinkedIn</u> - <u>YouTube</u> - Arlington, VA (*Willing to Relocate*)

I am a Senior UX Designer with five years of experience helping clients across the federal gov., healthcare, telecom, automotive and consulting industries. Successfully led projects, delivering user-centered solutions by understanding user needs, utilizing design thinking principles, fostering collaboration & incorporating iterative feedback.

- Design thinking
- Qualitative, quantitative res
- Visual, interaction design
- Competitive analysis
- A/B testing

- Design system
- Stakeholder mgmt
- 508 compliance testing
- Affinity mapping
- User interviews & surveys
- Managing UX team
- Wireframing, prototyping
- Usability testing
- User flows/personas/journeys
- Accessibility testing

Professional Experience

Senior UX Designer - CGI Inc. | March 2022 - Present

Received an Award in 2023 | Celebrating CGI's Values: Partnership and Quality

- Led complex digital products applications through multiple lifecycle and complex stakeholder management.
- Managed CGI's relationship with <u>Brightspeed Business</u>, leading design sprints with VP and marketing team to enhance customer acquisition, reducing customer attrition through improved CX with the launch of new products.
- Helped Brightspeed launch their brand online by migrating & redesigning 50+ webpages from Lumen and
 Centurylink to the new Brightspeed experience, while also creating 15 new AEM components to meet design needs.
- Organized a UX workshop with the client, which involved activities like affinity mapping, rose-thorn-buds, user personas/journeys, & competitive analysis to clarify goals and define immediate user and business needs.
- Led the migration of design system from Sketch to Figma, revamped guidelines, font system, color usage, buttons, and components across desktop, tablet, and mobile for consistency & reusability.
- Created mid to high-fidelity prototypes in rapid prototyping sessions to gather user feedback & drive iterative dev.
- Facilitated development meetings to comprehend coding limitations in Adobe Experience Manager (AEM) and provided feedback to streamline component development with time, resource, and development constraints.
- Leveraged Google analytics to track the performance of the product, which showcased a significant boost over **47% increase** in page views, coupled with a **45% increase** in unique pageviews, and a **whopping 70% drop** in bounce rate.
- Led a team of 4 product designers to design a VR experience where users can practice high stress social tasks to build skills and confidence. The initiative was to help CGI venture into XR industries.
- Designed infographics, logos, cover letters and brand elements for the State of Illinois, child welfare (DCFS) program.

UX/UI Designer - Softrams LLC. | March 2019 - April 2022

- Led a team of 2 researchers & designers to design <u>ACO Management System Medicare Shared Savings Program</u>, a
 healthcare product under the Center of Medicare & Medicaid services (CMS), a federal agency. Designed new
 modules in the existing system & collaborated with CMS stakeholders to establish product vision and MVP features.
- Re-designed existing modules with UX research methods, also advocated for clear UX writing and 508 compliance testing (accessibility) using wave/web-aim tools. According to the <u>performance results of 2019</u>, ACO-MS had a record year with users saving \$1. 2 billion in Medicare as compared to \$739 million in 2018.
- According to <u>performance results of 2022</u>, there was a significant user growth, with 66 new enrollments & 140 renewals. Over 11 million beneficiaries received care, reflecting a 3% growth of 324k compared to previous year.
- Delivered pixel perfect high-fidelity prototypes for a business contract, which resulted in a \$37 million program.
- Leveraged design thinking & led the research and design of a healthcare SaaS app (Hdrive) for file sharing and storing. This workflow involved affinity mapping, rose-thorn-buds, user personas/journeys, competitive analysis, user interviews & low to high fidelity prototypes to define and validate user & business needs.

Web Developer & UX/UI - Carmaguys LLC. (Co-op) | June 2018 - Dec 2018

• Redesigned and developed an appointment & scheduling app for car service and repair startup.

Education

Worcester Polytechnic Institute, Worcester, MA

Interactive Media and Game Development, Master of Science, 2016 – 2018

• <u>View Master's Thesis</u> - Designed and implemented a car driving simulator to teach driving rules and regulations, incorporating user research, A/B testing, and usability tests to enhance effectiveness and user experience.

University of Mumbai, India

Computer Engineering, Bachelor of Science, 2011 - 2015

Design

Figma, Sketch, Adobe XD, InVision, Balsamiq, Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Mural, Miro, Optimal Workshop, Google Docs, Miro, SharePoint

Business

Jira, Confluence, SQL, MS Excel, Salesforce, Power BI, Web analytics (Google Analytics), Pendo, Lucidcharts

Development

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, JavaScript, C#, NodeJS

Other

Premiere Pro, Maya 3D, Unity Engine, Unreal Engine, VR & Game design

Certifications

- Certified SAFe® 6 Product owner/ Product manager (POPM) certificate
- Certified SAFe® 5 Practitioner certificate
- User experience and interaction for AR/VR/MR/XR Certificate authorized by University of Michigan
- Foundation of user experience (UX) Design Google UX design certificate
- Conduct UX research and test early subjects Google UX design certificate
- Start the UX design process: Empathize, define, ideate Google UX design certificate
- Build wireframes and low-fidelity prototypes Google UX design certificate
- Build Dashboards in Power BI By Coursera

YouTube channel

- Founded and managed a successful <u>Youtube channel</u> focused on comic characters, demonstrating a strong understanding of the target user's needs and interests.
- Utilized qualitative and quantitative research findings to create captivating content that resonated with viewers, resulting in approximately 3.5 million views and 8 thousand subscribers within just 6 months.
- Conducted comprehensive user research, competitive analysis, and utilized Google analytics to gain insights into audience behavior and optimize content strategy.